Tanuj Sinha

Enterprise Manager at Browntape Ecommerce

Summary

Have a good insight of the market, strategies, competitors, practical approach and pragmatic application of various frameworks from experience of accomplished projects, working on global organizations in UK earlier. As MBA graduate, has in-depth understanding sales driven products and services. I utilize exposure of the 'real market' and product knowledge amassed to create better business plans within the best interests of organization and clients. Armed with an MBA degree in Global Business from Coventry University London Campus, UK, thoroughly understanding core strategies, global trends and research & analysis. MBA -Global Business molded with knowledge of various Marketing and Finance concepts, pragmatic application, Leadership skills, market research, marketing strategies, business planning, business development and skills as required by the current market environment. It adds the roots for a sound knowledge aspects of industry as a whole. In the past years, studying and working at the same time in a central business hub like London, gained a great exposure and understanding of current highly competitive market globally. A young, self-motivated individual with keen observation skills and ardent believer in excellent customer service and customer obsession. Hard working, multitasking & team player with confidence to work efficiently even under pressure and achieve targets, as proven in last organizations. I keep up the pace to be Enthusiastic, Challenging, Creative. I enjoy my work, discovering new solutions & keeping myself busy in various works. I Expertise with go getter attitude, adaptability and versatility gained through my past work experiences.

Experience

Enterprise Manager at Browntape Ecommerce

November 2014 - Present (9 months)

Responsibilities: Strategic - 1. Identifying prospective and target clients 2. Analysing economic and market data, compiling information from primary/secondary/published sources, prospecting. 3. Facilitating development and marketing of new products/services 4. Gaining and displaying expertise in the E-commerce business, developing deep product knowledge 5. Developing awareness about technical innovations happening in the industry Operational - 1. Pitching and getting new business for the company as per monthly/quarterly targets 2. Managing the sales pipeline including creation of contact lists, cold calling customers, sending proposals, following up to convert customers 3. Improving sales material 4. Establishing communication with target organisations 5. Developing relationships to grow revenue with existing clients 6. Coordinating with marketing team to undertake all types of marketing activities 7. Networking with corporates and prospects 8. Building a strong relationship with key top management personnel of clients, online marketplaces and channels.

Sr. Executive Business Development at IRIS CORPORATE SOLUTIONS

May 2014 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Looking for Business opportunity for the company on a PAN India level.

1 recommendation available upon request

Talent Acquisition Manager (Sales) at Cybertech Global Learning Solutions

April 2013 - March 2014 (1 year)

• Networking with prospective clients, generate business from the new and existing accounts and achieving profitability and increased sales growth. • Evolving market segmentation &penetration strategies to achieve targets. • Identify key/Institutional accounts and strategically securing profitable business • Played a pivotal Role In understanding the market segmentation and positioning the solutions after analysing the market demand and the customer preferences

Languages

English

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

Microsoft Office

Social Media

Teamwork

New Business Development

Management

Time Management

Team Management

Business Development

Market Research

CRM

Marketing Strategy

Leadership

Talent Acquisition

Business Planning

Competitive Analysis

Strategy

Education

Coventry university london campus

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Global business, 2011 - 2012

Jay Jyoti School

Tanuj Sinha

Enterprise Manager at Browntape Ecommerce



1 person has recommended Tanuj

"Tanuj is brilliant strategist with a keen eye for details.He is well adept at Client engagement, Lead generation & Product Demo. He possesses excellent communication skills and is surprisingly resourceful in closing critical issues."

— Ashutosh Kandhari, managed Tanuj indirectly

Contact Tanuj on LinkedIn